地球203
新哥谭
神谕  我是女猎手  请回复
Oracle, it's Huntress. Come in.
女猎手  通讯器基本无法工作了
Huntress, the comms are barely functional.
芭芭拉  你能听见吗
Barbara, can you hear me?
我需要更多的时间
I need more time.
能量波来得太快了
The wave's coming too quickly.
你必须现在就撤离
You're gonna have to evac right now.
我要在能量波来之前发出所有相关的数据
I'm sending all relevant data before the wave hits.
神谕  神谕  请回复
Oracle? Oracle, please answer me.
正在发送所有相关数据...
Sending all relevant data...
无限地球危机
地球一
需要拯救多元宇宙的七位完人
We have only located four of the seven Paragons
我们只找到了四位
needed to save the multiverse.
我们能找到其他三位  如果...
We could find the last three if--
我正在修理一台完人探测器  好吗
Hey, it's uh--repairing a Paragon Detector, okay?
这东西很复杂的
It's complex stuff.
有人呼叫后援了吗
Someone call for backup?
-爱瑞丝  -西斯科  谢天谢地
- Iris. - Cisco, thank goodness.
我正急需多一个有天才智力的人
I need another genius intellect, stat.
我正是因此而来
That's why I'm here.
这真是个超级完美的二重身
And that is a super doppelganger,
也是超级诡异的
which is super weird.
这还真是个全明星战队
Holy all-star squadron.
你们好吗  我是拉尔夫·德比  伸缩人
Hi, hi, how are ya? Ralph Dibny, Elongated Man.
准备好帮助大家大展身手了
Ready to help kick butt.
别理他  这是他第一次联合作战
Ignore him. It's his first crossover.
听着  这股反物质能量波
Listen, the antimatter wave
仍在多元宇宙间肆意破坏穿行
is still ripping its way across the multiverse.
我们必须尽力将所有人送到安全的地方
We have to get everyone we can to safety.
计算仍然显示
Calculations still show that Earth-1
地球一将会是能量波最后冲击的地方
will be the last place for the wave to hit.
我刚收到地球一艾丽克斯和布莱尼的消息
I just heard from Alex and Brainy on Earth-1.
我们从地球38救出来的所有人数仍有效
Everyone we saved from Earth-38 is still accounted for.
那么  目前我们应该尽可能
Then we should bring as many people to Earth-1 as we can
把所有人都带到地球一
in the time being.
我们成立一个救援队
Let's get a rescue team together,
去营救整个多元宇宙里我们能救出来的人
save who we can across the multiverse.
我能用通灵能力
I can use my psychic abilities
与乘波号保持联系
to stay in connection with the Waverider.
我也去
And I'll go as well.
平行地球上的乔纳森仍在罗里那
Well, parallel Earth Rory still has Jonathan,
我来收发通讯  有新消息就通知大家
so I'll run comms and keep everyone updated.
-超女呢  -我留在这
- Supergirl? - I'll stay here.
我们得想办法夺回我们的世界
We have to find a way to get our world back.
我想我们成功了  我们修好它了
Hey, I think we did it. I think we fixed it.
大伙  这些我们已经知道了
Guys, we already know all this.
它正在缓冲  有点耐心行吗
It's buffering, so maybe a little patience.
荣誉完人
我还真一点也不惊讶
Huh. Why am I not surprised?
爱之完人
我还真没想到
That's new.
人道完人
这家伙是谁
Uh, who the hell is that guy?
蔡瑞安博士  是我们地球上的
Dr. Ryan Choi, physics professor
青藤镇大学的物理学教授
at Ivy Town University on our Earth.
我猜那就是我们的下一站了
Well, I guess we know our next stop.
雷  拉尔夫
Ray, Ralph?
青藤镇  我过去常在那里混迹
Ivy Town. It's my old stomping grounds.
我们走吧
Let's go.
现在所有完人的身份都已经确认
With all the Paragons identified,
我们下一个首要任务
our next priority is determining
就是要决定如何阻止反物质能量波
how to stop the antimatter wave.
抱歉打断一下
Sorry to interrupt,
狄格尔先生到了
but Mr. Diggle has arrived.
莎拉  你怎么能让这事发生呢
How could you let this happen, Sara?
别人也就算了  你
You, of all people?
事情很复杂
It's complicated.
并不复杂
It's not complicated.
他需要我的时候我没在他身边
I wasn't there when he needed me.
狄格  我们正在想办法将他救回来
Dig, we are working on bringing him back
就像他当初将我救回那样  记得吗
the same way that he brought me back, remember?
你是说去炼狱走一遭
You're talking about a trip to Purgatory.
-是的  -行  我也去
- Yes. - Fine, count me in.
还有  还有些事情
And there's-- There's something else.
狄格  是莱拉  她
Dig, it's Lyla. She's--
她失踪了
she's gone missing.
-什么  -没人看见她离开
- What? - Nobody saw her leave.
她上一分钟还在  突然就不见了
She was there one minute and gone the next.
但她有瞬间移动的能力
But she has the ability to teleport,
所以
so she--
所以现在莱拉的位置
So there are now infinite possibilities
有无限种可能
for Lyla's location.
你给我听好了
You. Listen to me.
我不想失去奥利弗  也不想失去莱拉
I am not losing Oliver and Lyla.
所以废话少说  告诉我如何找到我的妻子
So cut the crap and tell me how the hell do I find my wife?
你听到他说的了  她在哪
You heard him. Where is she?
先驱者很可能和我的对手在一起
Harbinger could very well be with my adversary...
反监视者
The Anti-Monitor.
完人探测器
爱之完人  人道完人  荣誉完人
希望完人  真理完人  勇气完人  命运完人
反监视者
The Anti-Monitor--
这事已经板上钉钉了吗
is that, uh, set in stone,
还能不能有所转变
or can we workshop that a little bit?
这就是我一直在让你们做好准备的原因
This is why I have been preparing all of you--
测试并且挑战你们的极限
testing and pushing you to your limits.
我需要你们的勇气  你们的荣誉
I needed your courage, your honor,
你们强大的意志力
your strength of will,
甚至是你们信念里的真相
even the truth of your convictions--
任何使得你们成为这个地球
everything that makes you
或任何其他地球上最伟大的英雄的原因
the greatest heroes on this Earth or any other,
因为这就是打败我们的对手所需要的
because that's what it will take to defeat our opponent.
这家伙到底想干什么
And what exactly does this guy want?
消灭多元宇宙
To eliminate the multiverse
然后用另外一个宇宙来取代它
and replace it with another universe.
一个他能够控制的宇宙
One that he can control--
跟所有狂妄自大者一样
just like every other megalomaniac.
我早该预见到
I should've foreseen
我与先驱者的联系可能使他走向歧途
my connection with Harbinger could be perverted to his ends.
早该
Should have?
告诉我们怎样将她救回来
Just tell us how to get her back.
我和你们一样想找到她
I want to find her just as much as the rest of you,
但木已成舟的事我无法改变
but I cannot rewrite what has already been written.
我只能尝试去救剩下的人
I can only attempt to save what remains.
你知道将奥利弗的魂魄找回来需要做什么
You know what to do to get Oliver's soul back.
我会照看他的身体
I'll watch over his body
我保证一有先驱者的消息就通知你
and I promise you I will keep you updated on Harbinger.
收到
Copy that.
西斯科  也许你该给卡米拉回个电话
Cisco, maybe you should call Kamilla back?
不不  不是来电话了
No, no, no. That wasn't a phone call.
我正在剩下的地球上
I'm triangulating anti-matter wave particles
对反物质能量波粒子进行三角定位
on the Earth that are left.
为什么
Why?
我在尝试对能量波的源头进行定位
I'm trying to locate the source of the wave
根据这个显示
and according to this, it's hidden
它就藏在我们后院的一个地下区域
in a subterranean region right in our own backyard.
五分钟后到货舱碰头
Meet me in the cargo bay in five.
西斯科·拉蒙
Cisco Ramon.
我不是刚离开你了吗
Didn't I just leave you?
你不是一位完人
You are not a Paragon,
但你也有自己的使命
but you do have a purpose.
震波必须重生
Vibe must live again.
不
No.
不  我让超能力消失是有原因的
No, my powers are gone and there's a reason for that.
不管你愿意与否  都要回应这次召唤
You must answer the call whether you wish to or not.
也许你没听到我的话
Okay, maybe you didn't hear me
被你那浓密的络腮胡隔音了
under those voluminous mutton chops of yours.
快去履行你崇高的目标吧
Now go. Serve your higher purpose.
你确定还想我去吗
Are you still sure you want me to go?
是的
Yeah.
找到蔡瑞安  快去快回
Go find Ryan Choi and hurry back.
地球一
中城
巴里跑去哪了
Where did Barry race off to?
四周巡查
Perimeter search--
确保这不是反监视者设下的圈套
make sure this isn't a trap set up by the Anti-Monitor.
这名字让我反胃
That name makes me wanna barf.
你能回归太好了  震波
Nice to have you back, Vibe.
我们快点赶去纳什工作的地方
Let's just get to Nash's work site.
这边走
Right this way.
这倒是新鲜
That's new.
我们必须进去
We gotta get in there.
是谁
Who's there?
纳什  是你吗
Nash, is that you?
我已经不是纳什了  我是
I am no longer Nash, I am...
遭弃者
Pariah.
我是来做见证人的
And I'm here to bear witness.
见证什么
To what?
灾难
Tragedy.
新名字
New name,
新装束
new suit--
看来没人再来找我出主意了
guess no one's consulting me anymore, huh?
等等  到底发生了什么事
Wait, what exactly happened?
我像纳什一样在这些隧道里找马尔·诺武
I searched these tunnels as Nash for Mar Novu
试图杀死他  揭穿他是伪神
to kill him, expose him as a false god,
现在我被另一个神控制了
and now I'm being controlled by another god.
就是...
And that's the--
反监视者吗
Anti-Monitor?
他为我留下了完美的线索
He laid a perfect trail for me to follow,
但至始至终  他都在操纵我
but all along, he was manipulating me
这样他就能在这个宇宙站稳脚跟
so that he could gain a foothold in this universe.
你为什么不反抗他
Why didn't you resist him?
他的意志太强大了
His will was too strong
现在我被迫做见证人
and now I am forced to bear witness
看着他摧毁一个又一个世界
as he destroys world after world.
所以我们要阻止他
That's why we're gonna stop him.
你能打开那扇门吗
Now can you open that door?
不行
I cannot.
我变成遭弃者时
My memories as Nash
纳什的记忆就会消失了  但是你可以
are somehow lost to me as Pariah, but you can.
用震波唤醒那些记忆吗
By vibing those memories?
没错
Yes.
你看到了什么
What did you see?
进去的路
A way in.
你认为这本书能恢复那些已被摧毁的地球吗
You think the book can bring back the destroyed Earths?
太好了
Oh, too good.
我们没有时间了
We don't have time for this.
告诉我们如何用这本书
Tell us how to use the book
不然我就扭断你的手臂  你自己选
or lose an arm-- your choice.
暴力手段在哥谭市能行得通吗
Do the strong-arm tactics work in Gotham City?
这本书蕴含着古老又无穷无尽的力量
The book channels ancient and endless power.
需要强大的意志力和专注力才能成功
It takes immense willpower and focus to make it work.
你专注的是什么
What did you focus on?
他对超人的仇恨
His hatred for Superman.
一语中的
Got it in one.
但是这对那本书来说易如反掌
But that was easy for the book to provide.
你试试把书用在你所说的这种大规模事件上
You try to use it on the scale that you're talking about,
它会让你崩溃
and it could drive you mad.
就像迪根一样
Like Deegan.
卡拉  我们完全看不出
Kara, there's no telling
这会产生什么样的连锁反应
what kind of ripple effect this could have.
我是希望完人对吧
I'm supposed to be the Paragon of Hope, right?
也许恢复我的地球
Maybe this is my role,
阿尔戈和其他地球是我的职责
to bring back my Earth and-- and Argo and all the others.
我必须想办法解决这个问题
I have to find a way to fix this.
回头见
See you soon.
地球666
洛杉矶
那我们为什么绕道去另一个平行地球呢
So why did we take a detour to another parallel Earth?
这么多地球已经遭到毁灭
So many Earths are already gone.
魔法之柱摇摇欲坠
The pillars of magic are crumbling,
让我耗损严重
leaving me the worse for wear,
所以我不能带大家进炼狱
so I can't get us into Purgatory.
但是别担心  先生
But don't worry, squire.
幸运的是  我认识人
Luckily, I know a guy.
你们一定会很喜欢她的
Oh, you're gonna love her.
几乎没有她不愿意做的事
She's pretty much up for everything.
见到你总是很开心  路西
Always a pleasure to see you, Lucy.
是时候了
It's time.
抱歉  美女们
Excuse me, ladies.
看来想要我的不止你们
Seems like you're not the only ones who want a piece of me.
一会见
I'll see you later.
约翰
Johnny.
我本该说很高兴
I'd like to say it's a pleasure
能在我地球的俱乐部之外的地方见到你
to see you on my Earth outside my club.
但并没有
It's not.
你好啊
Hello.
我们应该还没见过  我叫路西法·晨星
Don't believe we've met. Lucifer Morningstar.
路西法·晨星  就是那个...
Lucifer Morningstar, as in--
-撒旦  没错
- The devil. - Yes, exactly.
告诉我  你渴望得到什么
So tell me. What is it you desire?
我
I--
I, uh--
我渴望救回我爸
I desire to get my father back.
老爸的问题
Daddy issues.
你们怎么不直说呢
Why didn't you say so?
我不知道
Look, I don't know
你的世界是否有一位奥利弗·奎恩
if you have an Oliver Queen on your world,
但我们地球上的那位已经摆脱了尘世的烦恼
but ours has, uh, shuffled off this mortal coil.
灵魂救赎  世界终结  废话连篇
A soul retrieval, blah, blah, blah, the worlds are ending.
全都是圣经里的桥段  约翰
It's all very Biblical, John.
好吧
Okay, okay.
我这么做是因为麦子的事  我欠你的
I'm only doing this 'cause I owe you for Maze.
没错
Yeah, you do.
对了  你让我想起了我哥哥
You remind me of my brother, by the way--
高个黑人  让我很是生气
tall, dark, annoyed by me.
你到底帮不帮我们
You gonna help us or not?
调情啊
Oh, flirt.
撒旦总是能帮人渡过一劫
The devil always sees through on a deal.
拿着这张牌
Take this card.
你在炼狱里的时间有限
You'll have a limited time once inside Purgatory,
在图片完全消失之时
and once the picture completely fades--
我们的灵魂就会消失之类的鬼话
Our souls will be decimated, blah, blah, blah.
并且将永世受困
And trapped in eternity forever,
所以我不建议这么做
so I don't recommend it.
我们扯平了  约翰·康斯坦汀
Consider us even, John Constan-tine.
康斯坦丁
Constantine.
是吗  随便吧
Is it? I don't care.
和凡人做交易总是很开心
Always a pleasure doing business with mortals.
他忘了告诉我们怎么做
He forgot to tell us what to do.
是吗
Did he, now?
欢迎来到炼狱
Welcome to Purgatory.
和那个炼狱很像
Looks a lot like Lian Yu.
中文就是炼狱的意思
Which is Mandarin for "Purgatory."
美丽的小巧合
Lovely little coincidence, eh?
知不知道老爸的灵魂为什么会选择来这里吗
Any idea why Dad's soul would choose to come here?
灵魂选择其牢笼
Souls choose their prisons.
奥利弗永世受困的时候
This place must be what Oliver thinks about
想的肯定就是这个地方
when being trapped for all eternity.
这也是件有趣的事
It's a funny thing too,
鉴于他的记忆可能遗失了
considering his memories are probably missing.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
奥利佛的灵魂一旦落到这里
The second that Oliver's soul landed here,
他的记忆可能会变得  怎么说呢
his memories would've been-how can I put it?
刷掉了
Squeegeed.
所以我们得让他想起我们
So we'll have to make him remember us.
该死
Bollocks.
咱们得赶快开始行动力
We'll have to get a move on as well.
这张卡已经开始消失了
This card is already beginning to fade.
当你和魔鬼合作的时候
Well, when you work with the devil
你永远不知道会是什么结果
you never know quite what you're getting.
完全没有压力  对吧
No pressure there, right?
周边安全
Perimeter's clear.
地球一上没有量子塔的迹象
There's no sign of any Quantum Tower on Earth-1.
你在这里做什么  遭弃者
What are you doing here, Pariah?
在这墙后边  是他的领域
Behind this wall-his domain.
绿裤子先生想说的是
What Mr. Green Jeans is trying to say
一旦我们进去  就可以真正地
is once we get inside, we can actually stop
从源头上阻止反物质能量波
the anti-matter wave right at the source.
好吧  咱们开始吧
All right, let's do it.
这个地方有些超强的震动频率
This place has some crazy vibrational frequency
贯穿其中
surging through it.
这个地方连接着
This place is the nexus
反物质宇宙与你们的世界
between the anti-matter universe and your own.
看吧  反物质大炮  这就是能量波的源头
Behold, Anti-Matter Cannon-this is the source of the wave.
各位  我感觉这个模糊是活物
Guys, I think this blur is alive.
让我看一下
Let me check it out.
不要
No!
巴里  怎么了
Barry! What happened?
是能量立场  我过不去
It's a force field. I couldn't get through.
那是地球90的闪电侠
It's the Flash from Earth-90.
他被困在了那个跑步机上
He's trapped on that treadmill.
那是地球90的巴里·艾伦吗
That's Barry Allen from Earth-90?
他是怎么到这里的
How did he get there?
监视者曾把他送走
The Monitor sent him away.
你别想对这里做出对我的地球做的事
You will not do to this Earth what you did to mine.
他被送到了虚空宇宙中
He wound up in the Netherverse
在那里反监视者找到了他
where the Anti-Monitor found him,
收割了他的速度
corralled his speed,
用来制造了他的反物质大炮
used it to build his Anti-Matter Cannon,
测试开火时
test-fired it...
毁掉了地球二
Destroying Earth-2.
-哈里没了  -杰西
- Harry's gone? - Jesse.
遭弃者  我们怎么阻止大炮
Pariah, how do we stop the cannon?
守护它的能量力场是基于反物质的
The force field that contains this is anti-matter based.
因此
As such,
所有正能量的物体都不可能穿透它
anything made of positive matter cannot penetrate it.
我们得把闪电侠从那跑步机上救下来
We have to get the Flash off that treadmill.
监视者说震波必须活着
The Monitor said Vibe had to live--
说他还有作用
that he had a purpose.
也许这就是了
Maybe this is it.
舍命一搏了
Here goes nothing.
感谢相救
Thank you for the reprieve.
但你们要放我回到上边去
But you gotta put me back on it.
各位
Guys.
反监视者给那跑步机设计了失效保险
The Anti-Monitor designed that treadmill with a failsafe
如果我从上边下来  它就会爆发
so that if I ever got off of it, it would erupt,
一瞬间消灭所有剩下的地球
destroying all remaining Earths at once.
我们只有几分钟的时间了
We only have a few minutes.
遭弃者  我们怎么...
Pariah, how do--
遭弃者
Pariah?
他去哪里了  他去哪里了
Where'd he go? Where'd he go?
地球一
常青藤镇
阿曼达  别这样
Amanda, please.
我知道红色天空很吓人  亲爱的
I know the red skies are freaky, honey,
但我可以肯定只是大气层的...
but I'm sure it's just atmospheric...
蔡瑞安博士
Dr. Ryan Choi?
干扰
disturbance.
宝贝  我得走了
Babe, I gotta go.
天啊  真的是你吗
Wow, is that really you?
雷·帕尔默博士
Dr. Ray Palmer?
我的天
Oh. Emm. Gosh.
我是蔡瑞安  很高兴能见到你
I'm Ryan Choi. It's so wonderful to meet you.
你的第二篇亚原子密度操控论文
Your second paper on subatomic density manipulation
是我微型化研究的基础
was the foundation for my work on miniaturization.
谢谢你  你知道我...
Wow, thank you. You know, I--
好吧  蔡博士
Okay, Dr. Choi,
我们需要你跟我们来
we need you to come with us right now.
你看到外边那片红天空了吗
Look, you've seen the red skies outside?
这个世界正面临末日
The world is ending.
帕尔默博士  这些人是谁
Dr. Palmer, who are these people?
我们是超级英雄
We are superheroes,
而瑞安  我们需要你的帮助
and Ryan, we need your help.
当然  帕尔默博士  真有你的
Sure, Dr. Palmer. Good one.
接下来你要说我被提名
And next you're gonna tell me I've been nominated
获得基础物理学的突破奖了吧
for the Breakthrough Prize in Fundamental Physics?
好吧  我们没有时间这么闹
Okay, we don't have time for this.
眼见为实  对吧
Seeing is believing, right?
要纸巾吗
Tissue?
你是  伸缩人
You're Elongated Man?
你们也是超级英雄吗
Are--are you superheroes, too?
我知道这听起来有些疯狂  伙计
I know this sounds cuckoo, pal,
但是你是一种叫完人的人
but you're what's called a Paragon,
也就是华丽点的说
which is a fancy word for saying,
"我们需要你的帮助拯救宇宙"
"We need your help to save the universe."
蔡博士
Dr. Choi.
如果世界正面临末日
If the world's ending,
我需要回家
I need to go home.
求你了  瑞安  我们真的需要你帮忙
Please, Ryan. We really need your help.
不  你不需要  我不是英雄
No, you don't. I'm no hero.
我是个丈夫
I'm a husband.
如果这是末日  我必须和我妻子孩子在一起
And if this is the end, I have to be with my wife and kid.
对不起
I'm sorry.
又一个地球已经消失了
Another Earth is gone.
多元宇宙已经只剩下七个了
There's only seven left in the multiverse.
真是讽刺
It's ironic.
我在看着历史上最大的事件
I'm watching the biggest event in history,
所有地球的毁灭
the destruction of every Earth,
而没有人会读到这个故事
and no one will ever read the story.
那些地球不是唯一被毁灭的世界
These Earths are not the only worlds destroyed.
我的世界被消灭了
My world died.
我的家人
My family.
他们是什么样的
What were they like?
充满了生命
So full of life.
他们是我的一切
They were everything to me.
只可惜我对他们的关心
If only I'd cared as much for them
并不及我的工作
as I did my work.
[外星语]
我现在明白为什么
I now understand why
你是那么成功的记者了  莱恩小姐
you are such a good reporter, Miss Lane.
克拉克
Clark?
我没能救下他们
I couldn't save them.
你想要歇几分钟吗
You wanna take a minute?
看起来你需要休息一下
Looks like you could use a breather.
戴上这个
Put this on,
这个标志
this crest--
我做了一个承诺
I made a promise
无论如何都将继续战斗
to keep fighting no matter what.
为什么要加上黑色
Hey, why'd you add black to it?
因为  路易斯
Because, Lois,
即便是在最黑暗的时刻  希望依然能够穿破
even in the darkest times, hope cuts through.
希望是将我们救出黑暗的光芒
Hope is the light that lifts us out of darkness.
我必须回去
I must go back.
这家伙不管从哪个地球来都不懂得放弃  是吧
Guy never quits no matter what Earth he's from, huh?
现在又是在自言自语
Now you're just talking to yourself.
变得更糟了
It's getting worse.
把我放回跑步机上
Put me back on that treadmill.
不行  我们会找出别的办法的
No, all right? We'll find another way.
-我在哪  -你是谁
- Where am I? - Who are you?
立刻把我送回弗里兰
Send me back to Freeland now!
淡定  电力男
Calm down, Electric Guy.
我的名字是黑闪电
The name is Black Lightning.
够了
Enough!
我把你带过来  杰弗逊  不是来打架的
I did not bring you here, Jefferson, to fight.
我带你过来是拯救性命的
I brought you here to save lives.
-你们都是什么人  -我是遭弃者
- Who the hell are you people? - I am Pariah.
他是杰弗逊·皮尔斯  在他的地球
This is Jefferson Pierce. On his Earth--
他是个教师  父亲  和英雄
an educator, a father, and a hero.
你是什么意思  我的地球
What do you mean, my Earth?
地球有很多个  杰弗逊
There are multiple Earths, Jefferson--
很多个像这样的地球
many Earths like this one.
你的地球
Your Earth...
刚刚被一股反物质波消灭了
Has just been destroyed by a wave of anti-matter.
那  那
So--so--
林恩  我的姑娘们
Lynn, my girls?
他们都没了
They're gone.
我把你传送过来帮助我们拯救人类
I transported you here to help us save humanity.
你应该救我的家人  而不是我
You should've saved my family, not me!
不是我
Not me!
杰弗逊
Jefferson.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
现在我们需要你的帮助去阻止这个反物质波
Right now we need your help to stop this anti-matter wave.
我无法想象你现在的感受
I can't imagine how you're feeling,
但是我知道失去自己的家人是什么样的感觉
but I do know how it feels to lose your family.
他们现在会让你怎么做
What would they want you to do right now?
求你了
Please.
所有世界都可能消失
All worlds could die.
你们需要我做什么
What do you need from me?
你身后的那台机器
That machine behind you
是反物质波的来源
is the source of the anti-matter wave.
我们需要关掉它
We have to disable it,
但是我们都无法靠近它
but we can't get near it.
你能承受得住这些能量吗
Can you contain that much energy?
只有试试看了
Let's find out.
不要
Don't.
你打开了那本书  你不知道会发生什么
You open that book, and you do not know what will happen.
对吗
Do you?
还有你要拯救的那些地球会怎样
To all of the Earths you're trying to save?
我必须要这么做  凯特
I have to, Kate.
那些人  他们需要帮助
Those people? They need help.
我们也竭尽全力在帮助帮得到的人
And we are doing our best to help who we can.
那可不是答案
That is not the answer.
那我应该怎么做
Then what am I supposed to do?
看着那些人死去问心无愧
Just be okay with all those people dying?
就像布鲁斯那样
Like Bruce?
坚信如果生命该结束  就不插手吗
Believe that if life's supposed to end, just let it?
不  当然不是
No, of course not,
但是如果你打开那本书  它会毁掉你
but if you open that book, it will destroy you.
我必须要这么做
I have to do this.
那么我就必须要阻止你
Then I have to stop you.
你挡不住我
You won't be able to.
你会意外的
You'd be surprised.
我也希望事情不会发展成这样  卡拉
I wish things were different, Kara.
我也想像你一样心存希望
I wish I was hopeful like you.
但是我知道如果你用那本书冒险
But one thing I do know is if you take a chance on that book
万一不管用并且你再出点什么事
and it doesn't work and something happens to you,
那我们就全完了
we're all doomed.
时间不多了  各位
Tick, tock, people.
我们再不解决这个问题
Black Lightning is gonna kill himself
黑闪电就要死了
if we don't solve this soon.
我们需要更多时间
Then we need more time.
我们浪费的每一秒都有一个地球消失
Every second that we waste here another Earth dies.
那能量波也离我妻子越来越近
That wave gets closer to my wife.
我曾经也有过一段婚姻
I was married once, too.
蒂娜总是说让我继续奔跑
Tina always said that keeping me running
是她生活的意义
was her purpose in life,
作为一个过去30年一直在奔跑的人
so as someone who's been running for 30 years,
我来告诉你  有时候
let me tell you. Sometimes,
为了找到做英雄的目的
in order to find your purpose as a hero,
你需要退几步
you gotta take a couple steps back.
改变一下看事情的角度
Reverse the way you see the situation
这样就会看得更广
and see a bigger picture.
就是这样
That's it.
我知道怎样关掉大炮了
I know how to stop the cannon.
这就是那天监视者在时间穹顶说的
This is what The Monitor meant that day in the Time Vault.
这也是我这些年奔跑的意义
This is what I've been running towards all these years.
是时候闪电侠消失于危机中了
It's time for Flash to vanish in Crisis.
翻转跑步机的速度方向
Reversing the treadmill's directional velocity
应该可以使反物质波撤回
could make the anti-matter wave recede
然后聚入神速大炮之中
and funnel back into the speed cannon...
摧毁机器与能量波
Destroying the machine and the wave...
结束这一切
Ending this once and for all...
让我摆脱反监视者的控制
Freeing me from the Anti-Monitor's control.
未来在何方  在此
Where's the future? Right here.
此命归谁  归我
Whose life is this? Mine.
你要怎样活下去
What are you gonna do with it?
不惜一切活下去
Live it by any means necessary.
一切都会没事的  我们会找到他的
It's gonna be okay. We're gonna find him.
你又不知道
You don't know that.
爸爸的灵魂可能永远就消失了
Dad's soul could be lost forever.
家庭是奥利弗的一切  他会回来的
Family's everything to Oliver. He'll come back to us.
奥利弗  奥利弗  奥利弗  等一下  兄弟
Whoa, Oliver, Oliver! Oliver, wait, man.
听我说  我理解你  兄弟
Listen to me. I see you, man,
真抱歉在危机发生时
and I'm so sorry that I wasn't there
我没有在那里支援你  但是我现在来了
to have your back during Crisis, but I'm here now.
我需要你回到我们身边
I need you to come back to us.
你是我的兄弟
You're my brother.
我不能失去你  哥们
I can't lose you, man.
我不能失去你
I can't lose you.
你好啊  约翰
Hey, John.
-米娅  你也来了  -那是当然的
- Mia, you came. - Of course I did.
她们很漂亮
They're beautiful.
我之前没机会介绍自己  蔡博士
I didn't get to introduce myself earlier, Dr. Choi.
我是来自中城的爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦
I'm Iris West-Allen from Central City.
你也是个超级英雄吗
Are you a superhero, too?
不  我和你一样
No, I'm just like you.
我知道这样要求很过分
Look, I know this is a lot to ask
而你想在事情最糟糕的时候与家人在一起
and you're right to want to be with your family
是完全天经地义的
when things go bad.
那你呢
What about you?
很显然你也有特别关心的人
You clearly have someone in your life you care about.
你不想在世界终结时死在对方怀中吗
Don't you want to die holding them when the world ends?
我的老公跟我们不一样
My husband's not like us.
他日复一日在外面去当超级英雄
He goes out there as a superhero day after day
为了保护他的城市不惜一切
and faces whatever he has to to keep his city safe.
那真的很勇敢  爱瑞丝
That's really brave, Iris,
但我不是这样的人
but that's not me.
你看  我跟你老公完全不一样
See, I'm nothing like your husband.
不  你是不一样
No, no, you're not.
你只是凡人  我们都有各自的目标
You're human, and we have a purpose too.
我们时刻提醒超级英雄们他们在为谁而奋斗
We remind superheroes what they're fighting for.
我的老婆  阿曼达和我
My wife, Amanda and I,
六个月前刚生下一个孩子
just had a baby six months ago.
西蒙
Simone.
我可能没办法看着她长大
I might not get to see her grow up.
你不想抱着她的时候知道
Don't you want to hold her knowing that
有了你的帮助世界才更加安全吗
you had a hand in making the world safer?
我去告诉我老婆我要晚一点回家吃饭
I need to go tell my wife I'm gonna be late for dinner.
刚收到露易丝的消息
Just got word from Lois.
又有六个地球消失了
Six more Earths are gone.
这是唯一剩下的地球
This is the only Earth left.
至少现在我们有瑞安
At least now we have Ryan.
你怎么知道如何说服他的
How'd you know what to say to him?
爱瑞丝
Iris.
怎么了
Hey, what is it?
如果就是现在了呢
What if this is it?
如果
What if
阻止反物质波是我作为完人的使命
stopping the wave is my purpose as a Paragon?
如果这是我必须做出的牺牲
I mean, what if it's the sacrifice I have to make?
如果是这样的话
Well, if this is it,
我不要你在没有我的情况下死去  巴里
then I don't want you to die without me, Barry.
我不想让你独自一人  我和你一起去
I don't want you to be alone. I'll come with you.
不  你不能来  爱瑞丝
No. You can't come, Iris.
也许我是拥有超能力的那个人
I may be the one with superpowers,
但是你的智慧  你的谋略
but your intelligence, your resourcefulness,
你的善良
your heart--
这是你的超能力  并且会帮你
that's your superpower and that's what's gonna help you
说服蔡瑞安  让他成为他必须要做的英雄
convince Ryan Choi to be the hero he needs to be.
巴里  我不想过没有你的生活
Barry, I don't want to live this life without you.
我不  我不想说再见
I don't-- I don't want to say goodbye.
我给你戴上这枚戒指时
When I put this ring on your finger,
承诺过永远会回家  回到你身边
I promised I'd always come running home to you.
如果我们分开  无论多久
And if we're apart, for however long,
无论我去哪里
know that wherever I go,
都会回到你身边
I will be running home to you.
你确定想要我离开吗
Are you still sure you want me to go?
去找到蔡瑞安  然后马上回来
Go find Ryan Choi and hurry back.
待会儿见
I'll see you soon.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
我不想和你告别
I don't wanna say goodbye.
我刚成为闪电侠时你们两个就在
You two were there the first time I opened my eyes as the Flash.
没有你们  我不会成为现在这样的英雄
I couldn't be the hero I am without you guys.
告诉乔和爱瑞丝我爱他们
Tell Joe and Iris I love them.
我们会的
We will.
抱歉  孩子
Sorry, kid,
我不得不这样做
but this has to happen.
巴里  你在干什么
Barry, what are you doing?
暂时偷走你的速度
I'm momentarily stealing your speed.
如果你做了足够久的极速者
You play the speedster game long enough,
就能学到些有用的把戏
you learn some neat tricks.
等等  你为什么要这么做
Wait, why are you doing this?
诺武说在危机中闪电侠必须死
Novu said the Flash must die in Crisis.
但他从未说过是哪一个
He never said which one.
你是个真正的英雄  杰佛逊
You're a true hero, Jefferson.
非常感谢
I can't thank you enough.
打开缺口
Open the breach.
我需要进入那个力场
I need to get in that force field.
不
No.
你想要你的朋友去死吗
Do you want your friend to die?
让我来  我来救你们
Let me do this. Let me save you all.
西斯科  不要
Cisco, don't.
西斯科  拜托
Cisco, come on.
谢谢  继续驾驭闪电吧  孩子
Thank you. Keep riding the lightning, son.
我知道你会让我们为你骄傲的
I know you'll make us all proud.
巴里
Barry!
他会死的  西斯科
He's gonna die, Cisco!
你让我做了队长
You made me team leader,
有时队长必须做出艰难的抉择
and sometimes, the leader has to make the tough choices.
我们不能留在这里
We can't stay here.
-我们走  -不
- Let's go. - No.
-走吧  -不  我还没...
- Let's go. - No, I'm not done--
巴里  快走
Barry, let's go!
-我不走  -快走
- I'm not going! - Come on!
我相信你  蒂娜
I have faith in you, Tina.
事实上  我也相信你
Well, the truth is, I have faith in you, too.
我不想打断你们团聚
I hate to break up the reunion,
恶魔
但是这个意味着我们得走了
but this really is our cue to make like a tree
把奥利弗的灵魂放回他的身体
and get Oliver's soul back to his body.
奥利弗·奎恩
Oliver Queen.
你是谁
Who are you?
吉姆·科里根
Jim Corrigan.
又是一个我认识的人
Another one I know.
但我还是另一个人
But I'm also someone else.
是另一个东西
I'm something else--
一个幽灵
a spectre.
滚开  疯眼怪
Take a hike, crazy eyes.
我生前是一名功勋卓著的警察
In another life, I was a decorated police officer,
靠自己的能力成为英雄
a hero in my own right,
但是我受到上了至高神明的召唤
but then I was called to a higher purpose.
现在轮到你了  奥利弗
It's your turn now, Oliver.
只有你能点燃导火索  奥利弗
Only you can light the spark, Oliver.
这是你的命运
It is your destiny.
什么是我的命运
What is my destiny?
拯救所有人
To save everyone.
否则  所有宇宙
Otherwise, all universes--
所有你爱的人都将毁灭
all the people you love will perish.
抱歉  但我必须这样做
I'm sorry, but I have to.
爸爸  不要
Dad, no.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
It's going to be okay.
-现在要做什么  -爸爸  等等
- What now? - Dad, wait.
我爱...
I love--
发生了什么
What happened?
爸爸不和我们回来
Dad wouldn't come back with us.
我很遗憾  莎拉
I'm sorry, Sara.
其他人的情况好一些吗
The others fare any better?
巴里的小队阻止了反物质波  还剩一个地球
Barry's team stopped the anti-matter wave with one Earth left.
我需要喝一杯
I need a drink.
感谢你帮助我们  杰佛逊
I appreciate you helping us, Jefferson.
我知道你失去了什么
I know what you've lost.
我的世界
My world...
我失去了我的一生挚爱
I lost the love of my life,
我的两个女儿
my two daughters.
一切都再也不会好起来了
Nothing will ever be okay again.
我知道
I know.
那个闪电侠  从地球九十来的闪电侠
That Flash, the Flash from Earth-90--
他样貌和我爸爸一样
he looked just like my dad,
亨利·艾伦
Henry Allen.
他是个很坚强的人
He was a resilient man.
因为谋杀我妈妈在监狱里呆了好多年
He spent years in prison for the murder of my mom,
一个我敌人所犯下的罪行  并栽赃给他
a crime one of my enemies committed and framed him for.
即便经历了这一切  他也从未失去希望
Through all that, he never lost his light.
在这样的时刻
Times like this,
我试着做到他那样
I try and do the same.
我的父亲
My father, uh,
阿尔文·皮尔斯
Alvin Pierce--
他也是个好人
he was a good man, too.
是个记者
Reporter.
一生坚持为无法发声的人发声
Spent his life giving a voice to the voiceless.
我12岁的时候  他被谋杀了
He was murdered when I was 12.
但直到今天  我还记得他教给我的东西
But I still carry the lessons he taught me to this day.
并教给我的女儿们
I passed them along to my girls.
我的女儿
My girls.
不管怎样  我明白了
Anyway, I get it.
听着
Look.
亨利和阿尔文的孩子不会轻言放弃
I don't think Henry or Alvin raised any quitters,
我们应该铭记他们的回忆
so we should honor their memory...
并怒斥
and rage...
怒斥光明的消逝
against the dying of the light.
出自《不要温和地走进那个良夜》狄兰·托马斯
狄兰·托马斯
Dylan Thomas.
很好  闪电侠
Well, all right then, Flash.
是巴里
It's Barry.
巴里·艾伦
Barry Allen.
杰佛逊·皮尔斯
Jefferson Pierce.
卡拉
Hey, Kara.
我  我能理解你想把这些人带回来
Listen, I--I get you wanted to bring those people back.
你有着我见过所有人中的最博爱的心
You have the biggest heart of anyone that I've ever met.
我只是不想看到你受伤
I just don't want to see you get hurt.
我必须说一句
You know, I gotta say.
对于一个
For someone who was unsure
不确定他们是勇气完人的人
that they were the Paragon of Courage,
需要很多勇气才敢做你做的那些事
took a lot of guts to do what you did.
也许吧
Maybe.
但是我相信还有更好的办法
But I have hope that there's a better way.
也就是为什么
Which is why--
也就是为什么我想给你这个
which is why I wanted to give you this.
氪石
Kryptonite.
你为什么会有
Why do you have that?
这是布鲁斯·韦恩的
It was Bruce Wayne's.
他失去了希望  但我永远不会
He lost hope and I never will.
留着吧
Keep it.
我有你永远都不会用到它的勇气
I have the courage that you'll never have to use it.
请注意
Attention.
爱瑞丝  拉尔夫和雷蒙德与蔡博士一起回来了
Iris, Ralph, and Raymond have returned with Dr. Choi.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
我跟你说了我会回到你身边的
I told you I'd come running home to you.
如果不是你  那是谁
It wasn't you, then?
是地球90的巴里·艾伦
It was the Barry Allen from Earth-90.
各位  这位是杰佛逊·皮尔斯
Everyone, this is Jefferson Pierce.
没有他的帮助
We wouldn't have been able to
我们就不能阻止反物质
stop the anti-matter wave without him.
等一下  所以  所以超人是真的
Wait, so-- so the Superman thing is real?
我的天  这么多年过去了
Oh, damn. After all these years.
这位是人道完人  瑞恩·蔡
And this is your Paragon of Humanity, Ryan Choi--
科学家  超级大脑
scientist, super brain,
准备好拯救宇宙
and ready to help save the universe.
你们具体打算怎么做
How do you guys plan on doing that, exactly?
卡拉决定不使用命运之书
Well, Kara decided not to use the Book of Destiny.
太冒险了
It was too risky.
先驱者  不像我  她可以去任何地方
And Harbinger, unlike me, can travel anywhere she wants.
所以我们怎么找到她
So how do we find her?
采取一切必要手段
By whatever means necessary.
我们可以从尝试
Well, we can start by trying
重新分配乘波号的卫星搜寻网格开始
to re-task the Waverider's satellite search grid.
莱拉
Lyla.
约翰
Johnny.
你还好吗
You okay?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我试着传话告诉你我当时正在地球一做侦查
I tried to get word to you that I was doing recon on Earth-1,
但是其他地球的毁灭
but the deaths of the other Earths
影响了我的能力
is affecting my abilities.
你在地球一的哪里
Where were you on Earth-1?
我  我想不起来了
I-- i can't remember.
没关系
It's okay.
我以为我失去你了  莱拉
I thought I lost you, Lyla.
没那么简单
Not that easy.
我只是
I just...
希望我能想起来发生了什么
wish I could remember what happened.
我们会查清楚的
We'll figure this out.
如果是反监视者
What if the Anti-Monitor
想让先驱者回到飞船上
wanted Harbinger back on the ship?
整个危机过程中  他一直在掌控着她
He's been controlling her the entire Crisis.
也掌控着你
And controlling you,
只允许你出现在他想让你看到的...
only allowing you to appear when he wants you to see...
一个巨大的悲剧
A great tragedy.
-莱拉  -莱拉
- Lyla? - Lyla.
不要
No!
是时候
It is time
结束英雄时代
to end the age of heroes
还有一切你们所珍惜的东西
and everything you hold close.
莱拉
Lyla.
那不再是你的妻子了  约翰·狄格尔
That is no longer your wife, John Diggle.
她已经被占据
She has been taken by...
-反监视者  -杀人犯
- The Anti-Monitor. - Murderer!
这是为了我的姑娘们
This is for my girls.
莱拉  你要反抗他  莱拉
Lyla! You have to fight him, Lyla!
全人类的命运现在就在你手上  遭弃者
The fate of all humanity lies with you now, Pariah.
我能做些什么
What can I do?
时机到了你就知道了
You will know when the moment arrives.
可悲
Pathetic.
试图阻止我真愚蠢  诺武
It was foolish to try to stop me, Novu.
不  莫比乌斯
No, Mobius.
允许你被创造出来才是愚蠢的
It was foolish to allow your creation in the first place.
永别了
Goodbye.
警报  地球一被毁灭
警报  地球一号已经被毁
Alert. Earth-1 is gone.
我们是仅剩的人了吗
We're all that's left?
结束了  无限地球都被毁了
It is done. The infinite Earths are gone.
很快就只有反物质宇宙能留存下来
Soon only the anti-matter universe will remain.
接近警报  附近监测到反物质波
警报
Warning.
28秒后反物质波将会击中飞船
The anti-matter wave will hit the ship in 28 seconds.
我知道我必须做什么了
I know what I must do.
发生了什么
What's happening?
爱瑞丝
Iris.
所有人前往舰桥  马上
Everyone to the bridge. Now.
你把他们送去了哪里
Where did you send them?
一个你碰不到他们的地方
Somewhere you can't touch 'em.
无论他们在哪  他们都会与你战斗
Wherever they are, they're gonna fight you.
不惜一切代价
By any means necessary.
到他们的最后一口气
To their very last breath.
刚刚发生了什么
What the hell just happened?
我们在哪里
Where are we?
这里是消失点
This is the Vanishing Point.
什么意思
What does that mean?
这是个脱离时空的地方
It's a point outside of time and space.
乘波号和其他人发生了什么
What happened to the Waverider and the others?
反监视者  他用先驱者来攻击我们
The Anti-Monitor-- he used Harbinger to attack us.
遭弃者送我们到这里是因为他知道
Pariah must have sent us here knowing
反监视者无法追到这里
that the Anti-Monitor couldn't follow.
我们得回去  我们现在就得回去
Well, we have to go back. We have to go back right now!
巴里  我们不能  他们已经死了
Barry, we can't. They're gone.
-有些不对劲  -怎么了
- Something's wrong. - How?
怎么了
How?
有什么不对劲
Something's wrong.
-我不能  -拜托
- I can't-- - Come on.
拜托
Please.
拯救  拯救
Fix it. Fix it.
我该怎么办
What do I do?
不要
No, no!
我可真庆幸这招居然管用
Oh, I am so happy that worked.
莱克斯  你做了什么
Lex, what did you do?
我拿着命运之书
Well, I held the Book of Destiny
看见你们七个完人
and I saw you seven Paragons
最终被困在消失点
due to be stranded at the Vanishing Point,
我想着命运可以
and I thought destiny could use
重写一下
a little rewrite.
莱克斯·卢瑟
那么
So...
我们现在要做什么
what do we do now?